Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm 5918 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm
1925- 1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Federation of Labor (AFL)
5918 mf
2.11 cubic feet
19 microfilm reels
Records, minutes.
Minutes of the Executive Council of American Federation of Labor, 1925-1955.
3294535
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, March 27, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 03, 2015
Scope and Contents
Microfilmed from the holdings of the George Meany Memorial Archives. Guide, compiled by Randolph H. Boehm, entitled: A guide to the microform edition of Minutes of the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5527 mf: National AFL Conventions on Microfilm
Labor unions -- United States -- Political activity -- History -- Sources; Labor movement -- United States -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Boehm, Randolph.; American Federation of Labor --History--Sources.; American Federation of Labor. Executive Council; American Federation of Labor. Executive Council.; George Meany Memorial Archives; University Publications of America (Firm)
3294535
- Minutes 1925-1927 (Reel 1)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of February 4-11, 1925. 118 pages., 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor departments consolidation; Iron Workers dispute with Philadelphia (Pennsylvania) Athletics baseball club; Bricklayers and Plasterers jurisdiction dispute; immigration restriction quotas; Carpenters Union dual national organization; Child Labor Amendment; American Federation of Labor visit to President Coolidge; private detection agencies and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, unions; resignation of Vice President James Duncan; German Federation of Trade Unions; Mine Workers dispute with Locomotive Engineers; prison labor model legislation; Franklin Roosevelt; Street Railway Employees dispute with Metal Trades Department; Teamsters disputes with Railway Clerks and Street Railway Employees; Union Label Campaign; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; organization drive among women office workers; organizing drive in southern states; boycotts; civilian military training.
  - 0119. Meeting Minutes of May 5-9, 1925. 60 pages., 2 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Recreation; Marine Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Steam Engineers; military training camps; ship subsidy bill; clerical workers, Stenographers, Book Keepers, and Accountants Union; Textile Workers Union dispute with American Thread Company; anti-picketing decision by Washington State Supreme Court.
  - 0179. Meeting Minutes of July 29-August 4, 1925. 106 pages., 3 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Conference among Machinists, Blacksmiths, and Street and Electric Railway Employees; American Federation of Labor tribute to William Jennings Bryan; Chicago garment makers unions, United Garment Workers Amalgamated Clothing Workers; United Mine Workers dispute with Coal River Collieries; federal restrictions on aliens; Child Labor Amendment; farmers relations with American Federation of Labor; labor banks; Railway shop crafts strike; Teamsters disputes with Railway Clerks and Street and Electric Railway Employees; Ladies Garment Workers Union application for prosanis (sanitary) label; workmen's compensation legislation in Massachusetts and Missouri; Mexican immigration; citizen military camps; Pan American Federation of Labor; strike against Pennsylvania Railroad; People's Legislative Service; Textile Workers wage reduction; organizing drive among women in industry; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0285. Meeting Minutes of October 4, 10, and 16, 1925. 39 pages., 4 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Federal restrictions of aliens; Asian exclusion; anti-labor bills defeated in 68th Congress; Book Keepers, Stenographers, and Accountants Union dispute with Ladies Garment Workers Union; United Mine Workers dispute with Coal River Collieries; immigration law violation by merchant seamen; workmen's compensation legislation for longshoremen; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Fire Fighters; mothers pensions; Oil Field Workers organization; sales taxes; Equal Rights Amendment.
  - 0324. Meeting Minutes of November 17-20, 1925. 106 pages., 5 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor opposition to conscription bill; convict labor; Fascist movement; Canadian and Mexican immigration; federal injunction bill; federal anti-labor legislation; Machinists dispute with Fire Fighters; Mexican Federation of Labor; Machinists agreement with Plumbers; World Court; American Federation of Labor financial and membership statistics.
  - 0430. Meeting Minutes of March 23-29. 1926. 126 pages., 6 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Actors union; Australian Labor Party; British Labor Mission to the United States; Carpenters affiliation with Wood Workers Union; Western Union suit against Chicago Building Trades; Steam Engineers disputes with Electrical Workers and with Marine Firemen; immigration restriction; deportation of alien seamen; delegation from Mexican Federation of Labor; organizing drive among African American workers; Watson-Parker railroad bill; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; workmen's compensation legislation in District of Columbia and Massachusetts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0556. Meeting Minutes of June 25-30, 1926. 95 pages., 7 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: American Bar Association endorsement of voluntarism in industrial relations; British Miners financial assistance; Fur Workers Union investigation; Machinists dispute with Street Railway Employees; workmen's compensation legislation in Missouri; radicalism; National Crime Commission; organizing drive among African American workers; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; Railway Labor Act; labor conditions in Russia; American Federation of Labor financial and membership statistics.
  - 0651. Meeting Minutes of August 24-30, 1926. 62 pages., 8 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: British Miners relief; Electrical Workers dispute with Railroad Signalmen; anti-union shop movement; citizens military training; employee stock ownership; voluntarism in industrial relations; Communist activities in Fur Workers Union; Russian labor commission; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; William B. Wilson's United States Senate candidacy; American Federation of Labor finance and membership statistics.
  - 0713. Meeting Minutes of October 3 and 15, 1926. 24 pages., 9 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Automobile, Aircraft, and Vehicle Workers application for re-affiliation; investigation of Communist influence in Fur Workers Union; American Federation of Labor conference with Mexican and European labor representatives; Eugene Debs citizenship restoration; federal immigration laws; Muscle Shoals power project; night work wage differentials; farmers cooperation with labor; Sacco-Vanzetti case; Richard T. Ely lecture on taxation; Stone Cutters Union complaints about pneumatic hammer; yellow-dog contracts; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey.
  - 0737. Meeting Minutes of January 11-19, 1927. 123 pages., 10 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing drive; Communist activity in Canadian labor movement; company unions; causes-of-crime study endorsed; American Federation of Labor Education Committee; Communist activities in Fur Workers Union; Italian trade union movement; Communist activity in Ladies Garment Workers Union; Mexican Federation of Labor; restriction of Mexican immigration; reorganization of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers Union; Navy Yard employees; Stone Cutters Union complaints about pneumatic hammer; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; Union Label campaign; workmen's compensation legislation in Massachusetts and Missouri; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0860. Meeting Minutes of May 10-17, 1927. 116 pages., 11 (Reel 1)
    Major Topics: Brewery Workers protest of Volstead Act; Bricklayers and Plasterers Unions agreement; suppression of union activities in Cuba; Communists expelled from Fur Workers Union; Indiana State Federation of Labor; Japanese Workers Union; Jewelry Workers organizing drive; Alexander Kerensky visit; John L. Lewis visit to Executive Council; Mexican Federation of Labor; Mooney-Billings case; labor delegation to Russia; Supreme Court decision on Stone Cutters Union request of antitrust exemption; Workers Education Bureau convention.
- Minutes 1927-1929 (Reel 2)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of May 10-17, 1927. 54 pages., 1 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Street and Electrical Railway Employees injunction case in Indianapolis, Indiana; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Pan American Commercial Conference; American Federation of Labor meeting with American Bar Association on federal labor legislation and court interpretations of federal antitrust law; Mexican Federation of Labor; Sacco-Vanzetti case; Canadian and Mexican immigration restrictions.
  - 0055. Meeting Minutes of September 7-13, 1927. 45 pages., 2 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor ban on Communist delegates; Electrical Workers jurisdiction controversy with Railroad Signalmen; indebtedness of Ladies Garment Workers Union; American Federation of Labor educational motion picture.
  - 0100. Meeting Minutes of October 1 and 15, 1927. 35 pages., 3 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Communist activities in Los Angeles labor movement; Carpenters re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor Building Trades Department; Mine; Mill, and Smelter Workers organizing drive; restriction of aliens; legislative reform of antitrust law; Canadian immigration restriction; Civil War veterans pensions; organization of African American workers; farmers cooperation with the labor movement; restriction of immigrant seamen, artists, and Latin Americans; Ladies Garment Workers struggle with Communists; Mississippi flood catastrophe; Muscle Shoals power project and labor standards; old age pensions; pacifism denounced; Pan American Financial Conference; aid to Puerto Rico; federal government employee protections; United Textile Workers organizing drive in the south.
  - 0135. Meeting Minutes of November 21, 1927. 30 pages., 4 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor conference with President Coolidge; American Federation of Labor conference with Pennsylvania Governor Fisher; United Mine Workers strike.
  - 0165. Meeting Minutes of January 17-25, 1928. 104 pages., 5 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Federal anti-conspiracy bill; Shipstead anti-injunction bill; Boulder Dam project; Mexican immigration restriction; Tom Mooney case; United Mine Workers strike; Communist activity in Seattle and Los Angeles labor movements; Teamsters agreement with Railway Clerks; Sleeping Car Porters organization; Street and Electric Railways Union New York injunction suit; American Federation of Labor petition for modification of Volstead Act; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0269. Meeting Minutes of April 24-May 2, 1928. 139 pages., 6 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Airplane Workers organization; Automobile Workers organizing drive; Boilermakers jurisdiction dispute with Bridge and Structural Iron Workers; Electrical Workers jurisdiction dispute with Railroad Signalmen; American Federation of Labor legislative proposals; labor exemption from antitrust laws; anti-injunction legislation; protection for union organizing; Child Labor Amendment; convict labor; five-day workweek; workmen's compensation for District of Columbia United Mine Workers strike; Pocketbook Workers Union, New York, New York, charter denied; American Federation of Labor platform to political parties conventions; Sleeping Car Porters charter denied; Tobacco Workers Union controversy with R.J. Reynolds; John H. Walker, labor delegate to foreign countries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0408. Meeting Minutes of July 31-August 7, 1928. 98 pages., 7 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor disaffiliation from Brookwood Labor College; Communist activity in Canton, Ohio, labor movement; indebtedness of Ladies Garment Workers Union; Leather Workers amalgamation with New York, New York, Pocket Book Workers; Mexican Federation of Labor; United Mine Workers strike; American Federation of Labor National Non-Partisan Political Committee report; Republican and Democratic party replies to American Federation of Labor political program; Sleeping Car Porters charter application; yellow-dog contracts among Seattle teachers; Tobacco Workers controversy with R.J. Reynolds; American Federation of Labor delegate to League of Nations conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0506. Meeting Minutes of October 18-25, 1928. 63 pages., 8 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor disaffiliation from Brookwood College; expulsion of Communists from Carpenters Union; indebtedness of Ladies Garment Workers Union; Mexican labor movement; Mexican immigration restriction; Machinists agreement with Street Railway Employees; Sleeping Car Porters application; Textile Workers Union strike in New Bedford, Massachusetts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0569. Meeting Minutes of November 18 and 25, 1928. 44 pages., 9 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Audit of American Federation of Labor finances; federal employees labor relations; Ladies Garment Workers; Shipstead anti-injunction bill; Mexican, Canadian, and Caribbean immigration restriction; federal farm relief bill; federal mine workers bills; Molders Union boycotts; narcotics addiction treatment bill; naval appropriations bill; ban on Chinese-made shingles; southern states organizing drive; yellow-dog contracts among Seattle teachers; Sleeping Car Porters charter application.
  - 0613. Meeting Minutes of February 18-25, 1928. 44 pages., 1929; 10 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Anheuser-Busch Company dispute with American Federation of Labor building trades; boycott policies; Brookwood Labor College; Cigar Makers and Tobacco Workers amalgamation; convict labor legislation; American Federation of Labor declaration of economic principles; immigration legislation; Shipstead anti-injunction bill; Ladies Garment Workers request for bond endorsement; narcotics treatment farms; Hoover commission to investigate prohibition; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Sleeping Car Porters issued federal labor union charter; American Federation of Labor Unemployment Committee; unemployment insurance legislation; Equal Rights Amendment.
  - 0723. Meeting Minutes of May 21-28, 1929. 134 pages., 11 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing drive; conscription legislation; convict labor legislation; immigration restriction policies and legislation; Ladies Garment Workers request for bargaining assistance; Hoover Commission on Law Enforcement; American Federation of Labor draft of anti-injunction legislation; discrimination against middle-aged workers; Mooney-Billings case; Pan American Federation of Labor; Sleeping Car Porters charter applications; unemployment programs endorsed by American Federation of Labor; "Progressive" faction in American Federation of Labor.
  - 0857. Meeting Minutes of August 8-20, 1929. 102 pages., 12 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Increased compensation bill for Army officers and enlisted men; Cigar Makers strike, New Brunswick, New Jersey; Communist activities in Fur Workers Union; anti-injunction legislation; loans to Ladies Garment Workers Union; United Mine Workers finances; Mooney case; Oil Field Workers organizing drive; New Orleans Street Railway Employees strike; Textile Workers Union strike in southern states; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0959. Meeting Minutes of October 6, 12, and 18, 1929. 32 pages., 13 (Reel 2)
    Major Topics: Cuba; Cigar Makers amalgamation with Tobacco Workers; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers dispute with Shell Oil Company; Automobile and Vehicle Workers organizing; immigration restriction; Mexican immigration; government employment conditions; coal industry legislation; forty-four-hour workweek; discrimination against older workers; southern states organizing campaign; Equal Rights Amendment; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; Textile Workers southern organizing campaign.
- Minutes 1930-1932 (Reel 3)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of January 8-17, 1930. 103 pages., 1 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor organizers retirement plans; prevailing wages in government contracts; Catholic unions in Quebec, Canada; convict labor; American Federation of Labor conference with President Hoover; United Mine Workers internal politics; Pan American Federation of Labor; southern states organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0104. Meeting Minutes of May 5-12, 1930. 152 pages., 2 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Bridge and Structural Iron Workers dispute with Tarrett Brothers Company; injunction relief legislation; coal industry legislation; Mexican immigration restriction; conscription legislation; convict labor; Filipino immigration restriction; Longshoremen's compensation; forty-four-hour work week; unemployment policies; United Mine Workers internal politics; unemployment at Navy Yards; Judge John J. Parker Supreme Court nomination; Owen J. Roberts Supreme Court appointment; Sleeping Car Porters international charter application; southern states organizing campaign; Textile Workers southern organizing; World Court; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0256. Meeting Minutes of September 4-12, 1930. 127 pages., 3 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Dissension in Alabama State Federation of Labor; American Legion relations with American Federation of Labor; request for modification of Volstead Act; Building Trades Department policy on jurisdiction disputes; Catholic unions in Canada; Cigar Makers and Tobacco Workers amalgamation; American Federation of Labor involvement in congressional elections; United Mine Workers and Progressive Mine Workers; Pan American Federation of Labor; southern organizing campaign; Sugar Beet Workers charter application; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; Textile Workers negotiation in Danville, Virginia; unemployment insurance; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0383. Meeting Minutes of October 5, 12, 18, and 21, 1930. 39 pages., 4 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Equal Rights Amendment; prevailing wages in government contracts; five day workweek; Sleeping Car Porters campaign to organize Pullman Company; southern organizing campaign; unemployment insurance; women's auxiliaries in American Federation of Labor.
  - 0422. Meeting Minutes of January 13-23, 1931. 180 pages., 5 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor Building Trades Department relations with Carpenters Union; Catholic unions in Quebec; convict labor; Hod Carriers jurisdiction dispute with Marble Polishers; prevailing wages on government contracts; injunction relief bills; Mexican and Canadian immigration restriction; immigration restriction; five-day workweek; Navy Yards unemployment; workmen's compensation; military training in public schools; railroad consolidations; Sleeping Car Porters; southern organizing campaign; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; Textile Workers strike in Danville, Virginia; Volstead Act modification; women's auxiliaries in American Federation of Labor; World Court; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0602. Meeting Minutes of May 5-13, 1931. 115 pages., 6 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Workers education; Hod Carriers jurisdiction dispute with Marble Polishers; United Mine Workers internal politics; old age pension model legislation; industrial conditions in Puerto Rico; Railroad Trainmen re-affiliation; wage reductions; war mobilization of labor legislation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0717. Meeting Minutes of August 6-19, 1931. 142 pages., 7 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Boulder Dam labor conditions; repression of labor unions in Cuba; Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Firemen; model injunction relief bill; Mooney case; National Civic Federation; old age pension bill; Pan American Federation of Labor; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; United Textile Workers strike at Paterson, New Jersey, silk mills; unemployment insurance; wage reductions opposed by the American Federation of Labor; World Court; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0859. Meeting Minutes of October 4 and 16, 1931. 23 pages., 8 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: Convict labor; five-day workweek; immigration restriction; motion picture industry, directly affiliated unions; bill on illegal immigrant seamen; unemployment policies.
  - 0882. Meeting Minutes of February 2-12, 1932. 136 pages., 9 (Reel 3)
    Major Topics: American Legion relations with American Federation of Labor; political parties national conventions; federal employee unions; injunction relief legislation; Machinists dispute with Street Railway Employees; United Mine Workers strike in Harlan County, Kentucky; Mooney-Billings case; motion picture industry and union recognition; old age security bill; prevailing wage rate on government contracts; United States Supreme Court appointments; industrial preparedness war legislation; Chicago World's Fair; American Federation of Labor financial and membership statistics.
- Minutes 1932-1935 (Reel 4)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of July 12-22, 1932. 120 pages., 1 (Reel 4)
    Major Topics: Bridge and Structural Iron Workers internal corruption charges; cotton legislation breach of labor standards; Federal Employees Union charter application; five-day workweek; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Carpenters; eight-hour day in motion picture industry; American Federation of Labor nonpartisan political action committee; American Federation of Labor proposals to national party conventions; racketeering in labor unions; American Federation of Labor charges against Steam Engineers; Theatrical Stage Employees charges against Motion Picture Operators; unemployment conference; unemployment policies; unemployment insurance; women's auxiliaries in the American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0121. Meeting Minutes of October 18-27, 1932. 93 pages., 2 (Reel 4)